mobiledevhq.com 2015-04-15

# TUNE | Privacy Policy and Your Privacy Rights

#### **Effective Date: September 15, 2014**

Tune, Inc. (“Tune”, “we”, “us”) is committed to protecting your privacy and the privacy of end users. This policy describes how we collect, use, and disclose information when you visit our websites, http://www.tune.com, [http://www.hasoffers.com](http://www.hasoffers.com/ "HasOffers.com"), [http://www.mobileapptracking.com](http://www.mobileapptracking.com/ "MobileAppTracking.com"), and [http://www.mobiledevhq.com](http://mobiledevhq.com/ "MobileDevHQ.com") (“Websites”). For information about how we collect information through our MobileAppTracking platform, please click [here](http://mobileapptracking.com/privacy-policy/ "MobileAppTracking Privacy Policy"), for information about how we collect information through our HasOffers platform, please click [here](http://www.hasoffers.com/privacy-policy "HasOffers.com Privacy Policy"), for information about how we collect information through our MobileDevHQ platform, please click [here](http://www.mobiledevhq.com/privacy-policy "MobileDevHQ.com Privacy Policy"). If you are an end user and want to opt out of our mobile app analytics services, please visit [https://www.optoutmobile.com](https://optoutmobile.com/ "Opt Out Mobile")

Tune has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy and Children’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/ "TRUSTe's program requirements") and [TRUSTed Cloud Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/TRUSTed-cloud/ "TRUSTed Cloud Program Requirements") including transparency, accountability, and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers information collected through our Websites and our MobileAppTracking, HasOffers, and MobileDevHQ Platforms. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy+mat@tune.com](mailto:privacy+mat@tune.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can [contact TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request "Contact TRUSTe here").

**_COLLECTION OF INFORMATION_**

We collect the information you voluntarily provide when you visit the Websites. For example, if you sign up for our service or request more information, we may collect information about you, your business, and others you add to your account. This information includes name, company name, website, address, email address, phone number and mobile number. 

When you visit the Websites, we automatically collect certain information about your computer or device and your use of the Websites. For example, we collect information about the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, your IP address, and the page you visited before navigating to the Websites. We also collect information about the computer or mobile device you use to access the Websites, including the hardware model, operating system and version, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information.

We use various technologies to collect this information, and this may include sending cookies to your computer or mobile device. Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory that help us to improve our Services and your experience, see which areas and features of our Services are popular and count visits. We may also collect information using web beacons (also known as "tracking pixels"). Web beacons are electronic images that may be used on our Websites or emails and help deliver cookies, count visits, understand usage and campaign effectiveness and determine whether an email has been opened and acted upon. For more information about cookies, and how to disable them, please see "Your Choices" below.

**_USE OF INFORMATION_**

We may use the information we collect for various purposes, including but not limited to:

  * Ensuring our Websites are relevant to your needs and to making the Websites easier for you to use.
  * Improving the Websites and our services, and providing general statistics regarding use of our Websites.
  * Delivering products and services, including newsletters and email notifications, confirmations, invoices, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages that you request or purchase, and processing payments that you have agreed to make for those products and services.
  * Helping us create and publish content and offering products most relevant to you.
  * Alerting you to our products and services, new products, special offers and promotions that may be offered by Tune and our selected partners.

**_SHARING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION_**

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, Tune will not rent, sell, or share personally identifiable information collected on the Websites with other people or nonaffiliated companies unless we have your consent, or under the following circumstances:

  * with third party vendors, consultants and other service providers who work for us and need access to your information to do their work such as providing customer support, processing payments, and storing data (e.g. Amazon Web Services). Any third-party vendor so used has agreed to protect the confidentiality of information provided by Tune;
  * to protect the rights and property of Tune, our agents, customers, users, and others including to enforce our agreements, policies and terms of use;
  * if required to do so by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or court order or in the good-faith belief that such action is reasonably necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request;
  * as part of any merger, acquisition, debt financing, or sale of company assets, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which information could be transferred to third parties as one of the business assets of the company.

We may occasionally allow other companies to offer our customers information about their products and services, but only when we believe that a significant number of our customers would be interested in receiving the information. We may also share aggregated or anonymized information in a form that does not directly identify you or any end users with any third parties.

**_YOUR CHOICES_**

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletters, you may opt out by following the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each communication. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional communications, such as those about your account or our ongoing business relations.

If you wish to correct or delete any personal information we have collected, please log into your account and change the information. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies. 

**_SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION_**

We use reasonable efforts including a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.

**_DATA RETENTION_**

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at support@tune.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**_INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER OF DATA_**

In the process of providing services to you, we may transfer information that we collect to affiliated entities, or to other third parties across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. By using the Websites or signing up for an account with us, you consent to the transfer of your information to the United States.

**_SAFE HARBOR_**

Tune complies with the U.S.–E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Tune has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Tune’s certification (listed as “HasOffers”), please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

**_CONTACT INFORMATION_**

If you have any questions, comments or suggestions about this Privacy Policy or the practices relating to this Websites, or other questions about privacy, please contact us at [privacy+mat@tune.com](mailto:privacy+mat@tune.com) or by mail to Tune, Inc., 2220 Western Avenue, Seattle, WA 98121 or by telephone at 206-508-1318.

More about cookies on tune.com

Using tune.com requires the use of cookies. If you do not want to accept the cookies for tune.com or from any of our third parties, you will not be able to use our service.

We use a cookie to remember your cookie preferences and this has a couple of consequences:

  * If you delete all your cookies you will have to update your preferences with us again.
  * If you use a different device, computer profile or browser you will have to tell us your preferences again.

The cookies used on tune.com and our other Websites are based on the International Chamber of Commerce guide for cookie categories:

  * For more information about cookies see the [further reading](http://mobileapptracking.com/privacy-policy/#further_reading "Further Reading") link below.

**Strictly Necessary**

'Strictly Necessary' cookies let you move around the websites and login to your secure account. These cookies don't gather any information about you that could be used for marketing or remembering where you've been on the internet.

**We use these Strictly Necessary cookies to...**

  * Identify you as being logged in to our websites
  * Remember things like information you've entered on forms when you navigate to different pages in a single web browser session
  * Help you use specific features like testing tracking links
  * Make sure you connect to the right service on our websites when we make any changes to the way the websites work

**Cookies we have defined as 'Strictly Necessary' cookies will NOT be used to...**

  * Gather information that could be used to advertise products or services to you
  * Remember your preferences or username beyond your current visit

**Accepting these cookies is a condition of using the websites, so if you prevent these cookies we can't guarantee your security or predict how our websites will perform during your visit.**

**Here is a list of the cookies we have defined as 'strictly necessary'.**

  * PHPSESSID

**Cookies provided by 3rd parties**

'Performance' cookies collect information about how you use our websites e.g. which pages you visit, and if you experience any errors. These cookies don't collect any information that could identify you – all the information collected is anonymous and is only used to help us improve how our websites work, understand what interests our users and measure how effective our advertising is.

**We use performance cookies to...**

  * Provide statistics on how our websites are used
  * See how effective our adverts are (we don't use this information to target adverts to you when you visit other websites)
  * Provide feedback to partners that one of our visitors also visited their website. This can include details of any products bought. This lets our partners improve their websites, but we don't allow our partners to reuse this information for further advertising
  * Help us improve the websites by measuring any errors that occur
  * Test different designs of our websites

**Cookies we have defined as 'Performance' cookies will NOT be used to...**

  * Remember your preferences or username beyond your current visit

In some cases, some of these cookies are managed for us by third parties, but we don't allow the third party to use the cookies for any purpose other than those listed above.

**Using our sites indicates that you accept the use of 'Performance' cookies. Accepting these cookies is a condition of using the websites, so if you prevent them we cannot guarantee how our site will perform for you.**

**Here is a list of the cookies we have defined as 'Performance'.**

  * aff_conversions
  * __utma
  * __utmb
  * __utmc
  * __utmz
  * _pmy_visit
  * _pmy_visitor
  * is_returning
  * chartbeat2

**Cookies provided by 3rd parties**

'Functionality' cookies are used to provide services or to remember settings to improve your visit.

**We use 'Functionality' cookies to...**

  * Remember settings you've applied such as layout, text size, preferences and colours
  * Remember if we've already asked you if you want to fill in a survey
  * Provide proactive live chat sessions to offer you support or submit a trouble ticket
  * Show you when you're logged in to the websites
  * Share information with partners to provide a service on our websites. The information shared is only to be used to provide the service, product or function and not for any other purpose

**Cookies defined as 'Functionality' will not be used to...**

  * Target you with adverts on other websites

Some of these cookies are managed for us by third parties – where this is the case we don't allow the third party to use the cookies for any purpose other than those listed above.

**You can control whether or not these cookies are used, but preventing them may mean we can't offer you some services, and will reduce the support we can offer you.** It's also possible that preventing these cookie stops us remembering that you didn't want a specific service.

**Here is a list of the cookies we have defined as 'Functionality'.**

  * app_user
  * swidth

**Cookies provided by 3rd parties**

Cookie | Host  
---|---  
edition | .tune.com  
network_id | .tune.com  
networkname | .tune.com  
networkurl | .tune.com  
__lc.serverchat1c | .livechatinc.com
